Jonathan Rainey

618-741-6448 | jonathanmichael5150@gmail.com | https://github.com/jonathan5150

About Me

IT specialist currently pursuing a B.S in Computer Science at Southern Illinois University at Edwardsville. I have 8+ years combined experience as a records information specialist, information systems technician, and administrative assistant. I have immensely enjoyed working with computers my entire life and strongly desire to learn the skills necessary to become a proficient computer programmer in the St. Louis, MO area.

Experience

Nursery Worker 2024 - Present

Home Nursery | Albers, IL

- Perform all essential duties of a plant nursery such as moving, trimming, watering, and disposing of plants, as well as maintenance on greenhouses
- Help customers locate and load up large plant orders
- Operate a Kubota track loader

Administrative Assistant 2020 – 2023

Tehandon Landscapes & Trees, Inc. | Breese, IL

- Performed administrative assistant and office manager duties, as well as fixed and maintained most technology related business issues
- Handled phone calls and solved customer service issues
- Planned work schedules, remedied equipment problems, processed payroll using an automated Excel document I
 created in order to save the business time, learned specialized software used for landscape design

Held unrelated part-time jobs while attending SIUE

2016 - 2020

Administrative Assistant

2011 – 2016

McKay's Business Concepts | Centralia, IL

- Managed most administrative and day-to-day issues including pick-up, transportation, and storage of confidential
 records from customers, management and delivery of confidential records to customers, handling phone calls,
 dealing with customers in person, administrative work with employees, creating schedules and itineraries, driving
 company vehicles, logging the day's activities, mailing letters, managing a full warehouse of records
- Handled hazmat materials, including pick-up, transportation, and storage
- Regularly used and troubleshooted every type of hardware used by the company, including computers, phones, routers, modems, industrial printers, label and barcode printers, industrial copiers, fax machines, scanners, digital typewriters, industrial paper shredders, etc.
- Regularly used and troubleshooted every type of software used by the company, including Intuit QuickBooks, DHS WorldWide's Total Recall, MS Office, and general Windows OS-based issues

Education

Southern Illinois University Edwardsville | B.S. in Computer Science Launchcode + Liftoff Coding Bootcamp | Learned Fullstack Web Development Kaskaskia College | Associate of Science Carlyle High School

In Progress Graduated 2023 Graduated 2015 Graduated 2011

Node.js

Skills

LANGUAGES		FRAMEWORKS	DATABASES	TOOLS
JavaScript	Java	 Angular 	 MySQL 	 Bootstrap

- **JavaScript Typescript**
- Java C#
- Angular Spring Boot
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- MariaDB
- PUG

- C++
- HTML5/CSS3
- ReactJS
- **OTHER**
- Windows OS
- MS Excel
- Android OS
- QuickBooks
- MS Word
- Virus/Malware Removal
- MS Excel
- Hardware Troubleshooting

Projects

Excel Timesheet | Automated Employee Time Calculator

2020

- Built a spreadsheet in Excel that automatically calculated complex employee timecards in order to bill clients the exact minutes per day they were on site working
- Was a good learning project as it taught me a lot about UI design, designing software for the next employee after me, and how to automate tasks with a computer, very similar to writing software to solve problems
- The business previously did this by hand, taking hours every day, after I finished my spreadsheet that time was cut down up to 90%.

Along The Way | Roadtripping Web Application

2023

- Worked with a group of peers to build a website that allows users to search for points of interest along a route using Google APIs better than the current Google Maps implementation
- Primarily focused on front end tasks such as our Google API implementation in Typescript as well as HTML and CSS styling
- Used Angular, Spring Boot, and MongoDB for the project tech stack

Portfolio Website | Personal Project Website

2024

Recent project I've been working on in order to learn React and in order to showcase my projects